DEVAN POTTER-BONAR

Ottawa, Ontario K2B 8L2

Phone: (613) 864-4869 | Email: devan.potter.bonar@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/devanpotterbonar | Github: github.com/Adpbonar

Portfolio: www.devanpotterbonar.com

SUMMARY

Endowed with a life-long dedication to learning, Devan is a Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Political Science and Communication. His experience in front line sales and marketing helps him excel at combining creativity and problem solving, to develop user-friendly applications that meet his clients needs. Known by his coworkers for wit, loyalty and attention to detail no matter the project; He is an asset to organizations that require team cohesion.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: English (fluent), French (functional), Robust writing, editing and research skills

Applications: Microsoft Office, Gimp, Audacity, InVision Studio, Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text, Zoom

Programing Languages & Frameworks: Ruby/Rails, Javascript, React, JQuery, HTML 5, CSS3

PROIECTS

devanpotterbonar.com | github.com/Adpbonar/dev-s-portfolio | www.devanpotterbonar.com

- A portfolio and blog app that showcases, my experience and articles related to my programming journey.
- Developed, by me, to facilitate my career change
- Languages used: Ruby/Rails, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap

NoteApp | github.com/Adpbonar/todo | notes-app-devanpotterbonar.herokuapp.com

- A note app was built in React offered. It uses an API to manage and render notes and tags.
- Developed as part of the University of Toronto Coding Bootcamp
- Languages used: Ruby/Rails, HTML5, CSS3, React

The TO-DO List | github.com/Adpbonar/todo | todolist-devanpotterbonar.herokuapp.com

- A single page todo-mvc application that features a fluid user interface. By using JavaScript users can rapidly add dynamic content.
- Developed as part of the University of Toronto Coding Bootcamp
- Languages used: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript

Flixster | github.com/Adpbonar/Flixter Project | flixter-devan-potterbonar.herokuapp.com

- A two-sided, video-streaming marketplace platform that features credit card payment capabilities. It also includes user role management, complex user interfaces, and advanced database relationships.
- Developed the app as part of the University of Toronto Coding Bootcamp
- <u>Languages used</u>: Ruby/Rails, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap

Devan Potter-Bonar - 2 -

EXPERIENCE

Director, Administration & Operations

2015 - Present

Bonar Institute for Purposeful Leadership

Ottawa, Ontario

As Director, Administration & Operations, wide-ranging duties including:

- Implementing a consistent brand design across platforms
- Creating marketing materials in print, online and on our app
- Developing methods to facilitate client interaction and ease the collection of information to complete mandates
- Adapting and entering content

Key Accomplishments:

- Coding in html5, selecting photos and designing graphics to showcase our brand experience within our app
- Evolving the brand to reflect app design flourishes
- Liaising with representatives of the app design company to articulate our vision and iron out issues as they arise
- Producing graphics and other promotional materials for the Bonar Institute websites (both English and French)
- Creating modals and customizing navigation of the site
- Ongoing upkeep

Receiver 2016 - Present

Shopper Drug Mart Ottawa, Ontario

As Receiver, wide-ranging duties including:

• Supporting the management team by ordering products and managing staff in their absence

- Creating positive strong relationships with vendors and taking the lead on inventory and backroom management
- Driving sales by taking on customer service and cashier management roles, as required

Cashier Supervisor 2012 – Present

Shopper Drug Mart Ottawa, Ontario

As Cashier Supervisor, at two locations, I was often the first management figure to interact with customers and ensure positive shopping experiences by:

- Supervising cashiers resolving issues as they arose
- Ensuring exemplary customer experience
- Troubleshooting technical difficulties
- Promoting customer loyalty, and addressing staffing and maintenance issues as they arose
- Preparing the daily store deposits

Cashier 2012 – Present

Shopper Drug Mart Ottawa, Ontario

As Cashier Supervisor, duties including:

- Supervising cashiers resolving issues as they arose, at multiple locations
- Ensuring exemplary customer experience
- Troubleshooting technical difficulties
- Promoting customer loyalty, and addressing staffing and maintenance issues as they arose
- Preparing the daily store deposits

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario

A 24-week intensive online program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, ReactJS, Ruby and Ruby on Rails.

Devan Potter-Bonar - 3 -

During this course, students built projects in using the Rails framework and React to learn how to code and hone our skills with algorithms. The culmination: An agile team project to enhance our skills and prepare us to work in this exciting field.

Coursework towards a Bachelor of Arts in Political Science, minor in Communication Studies: Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario